<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>John&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on John&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://johnardavies.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cloud 5: Introduction to deploying an app with simple CI/CD</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/technical/front_end/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/technical/front_end/</guid>
      <description>Patrick Staff&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;On Venus&amp;rsquo; at the Serpentine gallery
Deploying a web app with Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) Introduction
The last post used a Serverless approach to regularly search Twitter for particular words and then stored the corresponding Tweet data in a cloud database. Here we develop a simple Streamlit app that accesses the database and creates a page showing average daily sentiment on the topic. We then deploy the app in the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud 4: Using Serverless</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/technical/serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/technical/serverless/</guid>
      <description>La Cabane Éclatée aux 4 Salles, Daniel Buren at the Gori collection
What is Serverless? In previous posts we spun up virtual machines to work in the cloud, but the cloud can also perform specific functions for us without us having to run any servers, so called serverless computing. The servers providing the services still exist, but they are managed by the cloud provider while we deal with the services directly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud 3: Docker and Jupyter notebooks in the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/technical/docker_use/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/technical/docker_use/</guid>
      <description>Kings Cross underpass rotated, London
In the last post we covered some basic operations with cloud machines, in this post we discuss using Docker containers to replicate environments in the cloud and how to containerise a Jupyter notebook.
Docker has become a standard way to package applications enabling something that runs on one machine to run on another. It is a container which holds a virtualisation of an operating system within which applications can be packaged to allow them to move between machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud 2: Getting started with using a Virtual Machine in the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/technical/cloud_use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/technical/cloud_use/</guid>
      <description>Clouds over the Lea valley, London
In the last post we covered setting up a virtual machine in the cloud, logging into it via ssh and securing it. However, this gets us a virtual machine running in the cloud costing us money, it isn&amp;rsquo;t doing anything useful. To work with the virtual machine there are some other basic things that it&amp;rsquo;s helpful to be able to do.
1. Getting things on and off the cloud machine</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Simulation Machine: The digital issue we don’t talk about and its implications for the creative economy</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/simulation_machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/simulation_machine/</guid>
      <description>The digital issue we don’t discuss and its implications for the creative economy Computers’ ability to effectively simulate a huge variety of functions has allowed them to replace hi-fis, cameras, maps, DVD players, calculators, typewriters, cash registers, musical instruments, watches, TVs, newspapers, books, shopfronts, money and more. Although the changes caused by the general-purpose power of computation are widely observed, it is arguably less discussed than the role of data and/or the costless copying of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visions and Reality - Can blockchain allow us to rethink the creative industries?</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/blockchain_creative/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/blockchain_creative/</guid>
      <description>What is the blockchain? What creative industry issues might it address? and what are some of the practical barriers?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Street Style: Machine learning takes to the streets</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/street_style/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/street_style/</guid>
      <description>Streets surround us, but, at first glance, there is no systematic data on what they look like. There are records of property transactions, land use and buildings protected due to architectural or historic significance (listed buildings and conservation areas), although none of these directly capture areas’ appearance.
Buildings appearance is though part of planning decisions about the built environment. There is also greater recognition of the importance of areas having a sense of place, but it is not always clear what this means and how to measure it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freeing our Minds - Three ways digital technologies could radically change art</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/freeing_our_minds/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/freeing_our_minds/</guid>
      <description>An algorithmic Deep Dream at the school of Athens, John Davies
From algorithmic creations to transforming galleries Art is free. It doesn’t need to represent anything. It doesn’t need to be beautiful. It doesn’t need to be an object. It doesn’t need to be new. Despite these liberations, it is notable how comparatively little artists&#39; tools have changed. Particularly when compared to the digital revolution’s effect on many other creative domains, with entire supply chains collapsing to a laptop, some servers and an internet connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal designs - how to avoid the pitfalls of grand landmark building projects?</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/optimal_designs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/optimal_designs/</guid>
      <description>The Eiffel Tower, the Sydney Opera House, the London Garden Bridge.
The recent demise of the proposed Garden Bridge across the Thames raises the question of when public support for radical buildings should occur. Unique buildings, by their nature, are hard to evaluate based on experience and their construction can turn out to be unexpectedly expensive. However, they have also resulted in some of the world’s most popular and distinctive buildings – central to many cities’ identity and tourism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collective action and anonymity - two tools to stimulate innovation in the data economy</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/collective_action/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/collective_action/</guid>
      <description>Data is different from other assets like gold and oil in that almost all of us, as individuals, generate it. Giving us more control over our own data will stimulate innovation, but realising the full potential will also involve collective action and anonymisation.
Power to the people: Giving us control over our own data We should be empowered to control our own data. This is due to our part in its creation, our right to privacy for our personal information, the growing likelihood that this data will be processed in ways that affect us, but also the economic and social good that can be realised from it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User illusions: Data and algorithms will address long-standing consumer issues, but create new ones too</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/user_illusions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/user_illusions/</guid>
      <description>Why consumer choice and data protection are becoming much more connected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative networks: why social media is getting creative</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/creative_social_networks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/creative_social_networks/</guid>
      <description>Why are we seeing more networks in creative domains</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opening up: Maximising open data’s impact is about incentives and rethinking the boundary of the state</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/open_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/open_data/</guid>
      <description> Maximising open data’s impact is about incentives and rethinking the boundary of the state</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Affair of Style: how social media is affecting fashion</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/fashion_socialmedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/fashion_socialmedia/</guid>
      <description>Styles, trends and brands Fashion has tensions. It’s about standing out. It’s about being noticed. It’s also about belonging and clothes as a signal of status, desirability and taste. There are many ways to stand out - not all of them are good. Although there are objective measures of quality, such as the technical skill and materials garments are constructed with, styles have a degree of subjectivity. At any one time specific looks may be in, and the reasons for this are not particularly clear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fun Times: The UK&#39;s new business department</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/fun_times/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/fun_times/</guid>
      <description>The digital rise of the Department for Culture, Media and Sport</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The edge of cool - places have it, then they lose it, but should we care?</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/edge_of_cool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/edge_of_cool/</guid>
      <description>Why we should care about creative and cultural displacement in cities</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selling yourself: four issues and four implications about markets for personal data</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/selling_yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/selling_yourself/</guid>
      <description>Establishing new markets where things can be priced and traded creates incentives for people and companies to work out how much something is worth to them and to trade and innovate accordingly. It is hoped that allowing us a greater ability to control access to our personal data, in exchange for services and money, could encourage similar benefits.[1]
Part of this may involve the growth of Personal Information Management Services (PIMS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HAL&#39;s revenge: The computer as 21st century reviewer</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/hals_revenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/hals_revenge/</guid>
      <description>In the 21st century we will increasingly see computers assessing art</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Price of Being Free: We may care about our data, but do we value it?</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/price_of_being_free/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/price_of_being_free/</guid>
      <description>‘Something is free, if someone else pays’ - Anon.
We get many free goods and services online via an opaque barter where, in exchange, companies access our data and try and sell us things. We say we care about our data[1], though if we could retain it, but pay for these products, would we? This option is not always available, but even if it was, it is not clear that we would take it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The virtual and the physical: The growth of social media data on places, and its implications</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/virtual_physical/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/virtual_physical/</guid>
      <description>Geotagged Flickr photography in and around Hyde Park in London. Sights with visibly high levels of activity include the Serpentine, the museums in Exhibition Road. Image John Davies
Into the city In the past, people walked the streets and left no trace. This is no longer true. We are creating large amounts of data about the places around us: how we move through them, and how they move us. One source of this data has been the growth in smart phone and social media use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dissolving the House: a technological solution to the House of Lords?</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/dissolving_the_house/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/dissolving_the_house/</guid>
      <description>We should change the terms of debate on the future of the House of Lords</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Glass Tower: why online learning will and won&#39;t change higher education</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/the_glass_tower/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/the_glass_tower/</guid>
      <description>“But we don&amp;rsquo;t want to teach &amp;lsquo;em,&amp;quot; replied the Badger. &amp;ldquo;We want to learn &amp;lsquo;em” Wind in the Willows, Kenneth Grahame.*
We are told that the future of the UK economy lies in a better educated, and hence more productive, workforce. Some of this extra productivity is expected to come from the intellectual benefits of higher education - an area where there is an ever greater focus on student choice. What is less often noted is that the market for university degrees has many characteristics which make it difficult for student choice to drive higher levels of teaching quality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sampling Society: The foundations of a new frontier in understanding society</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/sampling_society/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/sampling_society/</guid>
      <description>Geotagged photos in central London, John Davies. Image based on the locations of over a million geo-tagged photos on Flickr by 38,255 photographers or, at least, photo accounts.
Social media data, such as that produced by Twitter and Facebook use, is opening up new ways to understand society, but how do people obtain this data, and what are the challenges in using it to learn about our lives?
API days</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heritage in Space: Can social media data help us understand our relationship with historic buildings?</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/heritage_in_space/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/heritage_in_space/</guid>
      <description>Locations of geo-tagged photographs taken in central and inner London
The new tracks Cities are carpeted with pictures, but these pictures are not public art or the work of a subversive street artist. They are the geo-tagged photos continuously being uploaded to sites like Flickr and Twitter. This is creating a new world to explore. A world which could change how we think about the built environment and its heritage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The pin factory and the universal machine: the future of 3D printing via the ideas of Adam Smith and Alan Turing</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/pin_factory/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/pin_factory/</guid>
      <description>The Printers won’t kill the Pin Factory To hear some of the talk around 3D printers one could be forgiven for thinking they’ll transform us all into a collection of skilled artisans creating in our bedrooms. Regardless of what one makes of other spectres that have been raised (neighbours running off 3D guns and the undermining of copyright) this seems an undeniably attractive image. Though it probably won&amp;rsquo;t be quite like that in reality, for a rather old-fashioned reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud 1: Introduction to launching a Virtual Machine in the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/technical/cloud_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/technical/cloud_intro/</guid>
      <description>Es Devlin&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;BLUEWHITESKY&amp;rdquo; at the 2021 LUX exhibition
More and more of the digital services we use involve the cloud, where the computing is not done on our laptop or mobile, but accessed over the internet. However, coming across its technical details for the first time, the cloud can be slightly opaque to someone whose background is not computing - I certainly found it that way. From a data science perspective working with it involves things that are not related to statistics, machine learning or even programming narrowly defined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/contact/</guid>
      <description>   var submitted=false;   Feel free to get in touch via the form below Name Email Subject Message  Send   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative industries</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/creative_industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/creative_industries/</guid>
      <description>The creative industries are a closely connected set of sectors including art, design, fashion, film, music and computer games.
Some of the things I have written on the creative industries are here and I have spoken at many conferences and events on it. An interview with Design Decode is here.
In addition to public data science work and commentary, I have worked as a data scientist and economist for some of the UK&amp;rsquo;s largest cultural institutions and attractions on their visitor and membership data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Waterfront: Thames estuary plans show changing attitudes to creative industries</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/on_the_waterfront/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/on_the_waterfront/</guid>
      <description>In the 1970s, London’s Docklands area stretched empty and derelict east of the city centre. The wharves that had provided employment for tens of thousands standing deserted for mile upon mile along the Thames. The shift to containers for shipping had made the docks too small and put them out of business.
To fill this vacuum came what was then the largest regeneration scheme in Europe. The redevelopment of the docks, heavily underpinned by government tax breaks, was mainly focused on financial services, pre-digital media i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Other data projects</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/other_data_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/other_data_projects/</guid>
      <description>In addition to work on the creative industries I have done a number of other data projects.
Mapping city-level food access In partnership with the Liverpool good food initative I developed an interactive map that shows levels of access to food in the city. The map allows food supply within the city to be visualised in terms of areas that are further away from food support initatives and which due to higher levels of deprivation are potentially at greater risk of food insecurity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>talks</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/talks/</guid>
      <description>I have spoken at many conferences and events globally, including:
  Public spaces - internet for the common good conference, 12th March, 2021
  Cross Innovation Conference, Hamburg Kreativ Gesellschaft, 2nd December, 2020
  Coronavirus (COVID-19) and museums: impact, innovations and planning for post-crisis, OECD, 10th April, 2020
  Beyond conference research symposium, Edinburgh, 21st November, 2019
  Internationale Fachkonferenz 2019, Berlin, October 30th, 2019</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thankyou</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/thankyou/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/thankyou/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
