<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>social media on John&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/tags/social-media/</link>
    <description>Recent content in social media on John&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://johnardavies.github.io/tags/social-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Affair of Style: how social media is affecting fashion</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/fashion_socialmedia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/fashion_socialmedia/</guid>
      <description>Styles, trends and brands Fashion has tensions. It’s about standing out. It’s about being noticed. It’s also about belonging and clothes as a signal of status, desirability and taste. There are many ways to stand out - not all of them are good. Although there are objective measures of quality, such as the technical skill and materials garments are constructed with, styles have a degree of subjectivity. At any one time specific looks may be in, and the reasons for this are not particularly clear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The virtual and the physical: The growth of social media data on places, and its implications</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/virtual_physical/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/virtual_physical/</guid>
      <description>Locations of geo-tagged photographs taken in central and inner London
Into the city In the past, people walked the streets and left no trace. This is no longer true. We are creating large amounts of data about the places around us: how we move through them, and how they move us. One source of this data has been the growth in smart phone and social media use.[1] The geotagged social media data generated by phones and cameras is producing information on a large number of people’s interactions with their surroundings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heritage in Space: Can social media data help us understand our relationship with historic buildings?</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/heritage_in_space/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/heritage_in_space/</guid>
      <description>Locations of geo-tagged photographs taken in central and inner London
The new tracks Cities are carpeted with pictures, but these pictures are not public art or the work of a subversive street artist. They are the geo-tagged photos continuously being uploaded to sites like Flickr and Twitter. This is creating a new world to explore. A world which could change how we think about the built environment and its heritage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
