<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>built environment on John&#39;s Site</title>
    <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/tags/built-environment/</link>
    <description>Recent content in built environment on John&#39;s Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://johnardavies.github.io/tags/built-environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optimal designs - how to avoid the pitfalls of grand landmark building projects?</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/landmark_buildings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/landmark_buildings/</guid>
      <description>The Eiffel Tower, the Sydney Opera House, the London Garden Bridge.
The recent demise of the proposed Garden Bridge across the Thames raises the question of when public support for radical buildings should occur. Unique buildings, by their nature, are hard to evaluate based on experience and their construction can turn out to be unexpectedly expensive. However, they have also resulted in some of the world’s most popular and distinctive buildings – central to many cities’ identity and tourism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The edge of cool - places have it, then they lose it, but should we care?</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/edge_of_cool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/edge_of_cool/</guid>
      <description>Why we should care about creative and cultural displacement in cities</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The virtual and the physical: The growth of social media data on places, and its implications</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/virtual_physical/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/virtual_physical/</guid>
      <description>Into the city In the past, people walked the streets and left no trace. This is no longer true. We are creating large amounts of data about the places around us: how we move through them, and how they move us. One source of this data has been the growth in smart phone and social media use.[1] The geotagged social media data generated by phones and cameras is producing information on a large number of people’s interactions with their surroundings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heritage in Space: Can social media help us better understand our relationship with historic buildings?</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/heritage_in_space/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/heritage_in_space/</guid>
      <description>The new tracks Cities are carpeted with pictures, but these pictures are not public art or the work of a subversive street artist. They are the geo-tagged photos continuously being uploaded to sites like Flickr and Twitter. This is creating a new world to explore. A world which could change how we think about the built environment and its heritage.
We know that people engage with heritage (around half the adult English population visit for pleasure a historic town or city in a given year), however, visitor numbers aside, the details of this have always been a bit hazy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Waterfront: Thames estuary plans show changing attitudes to creative industries</title>
      <link>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/waterfront/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://johnardavies.github.io/posts/waterfront/</guid>
      <description>In the 1970s, London’s Docklands area stretched empty and derelict east of the city centre. The wharves that had provided employment for tens of thousands standing deserted for mile upon mile along the Thames. The shift to containers for shipping had made the docks too small and put them out of business.
To fill this vacuum came what was then the largest regeneration scheme in Europe. The redevelopment of the docks, heavily underpinned by government tax breaks, was mainly focused on financial services, pre-digital media i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
